黑客帝国
电话  已接通
-一切就绪了吗  -今天不是你接班
- Is everything in place? - You weren't supposed to relieve me.
追踪程序  运行中
我知道  但我就是想接
I know, but I felt like taking a shift.
你喜欢他  是吗  喜欢看着他
You like him, don't you? You like watching him.
-别胡扯了  -他会死的  你知道的吧
- Don't be ridiculous. - We're gonna kill him, you understand?
墨菲斯认为他就是救世主
Morpheus believes he is the One.
-你也这么想吗  -我怎么想不重要
- Do you? - It doesn't matter what I believe.
你不这么想  是吗
You don't, do you?
-你听到了吗  -听到什么
- Did you hear that? - Hear what?
你确定这条线路安全吗
Are you sure this line is clean?
当然确定
Yeah, of course I'm sure.
我得走了
I better go.
-别动  警察  -双手抱头
- Freeze! Police! - Hands on your head!
快点  立刻抱头
Do it! Do it now!
警督
Lieutenant.
我操
Oh, shit.
警督  我给你的命令很明确
Lieutenant, you were given specific orders.
我只是在做事而已
I'm just doing my job.
少跟我说"这个归我管"
You give me that "Juris-my-dick-tion" crap,
趁早闭嘴吧
you can cram it up your ass.
给你的命令是为了保护你们的安全
The orders were for your protection.
一个小姑娘我们还是对付得了的
I think we can handle one little girl.
我派了两队人上去
I sent two units!
他们马上就会把她带下来
They're bringing her down now!
不  警督  你的人已经死了
No, lieutenant, your men are already dead.
操
Shit.
墨菲斯  线路被追踪了  我不知道是怎么回事
Morpheus, the line was traced. I don't know how.
我知道  他们切断了线路
I know, they cut the hard line.
没时间了  你必须走其他出口
There's no time, you're gonna have to get to another exit.
-有特工在吗  -有
- Are there any agents? - Yes.
天杀的
Goddamn it.
你必须专心  崔妮蒂
You have to focus, Trinity.
威尔斯和雷克街路口有个公共电话
There's a phone at Wells and Lake,
你可以做到的
you can make it.
-好吧  -去吧
- All right. - Go,
这怎么可能
That's impossible.
起来  崔妮蒂  快起来
Get up, Trinity. Just get up.
起来
Get up.
她跑了
She got out.
没关系
It doesn't matter.
-线人很可靠  -是的
- The informant is real. - Yes
我们知道他们下一个目标是谁了
We have the name of their next target.
他叫尼奥
The name is Neo.
需要尽快展开搜寻
We'll need a search running.
已经在查了
It has already begun.
搜索中
醒醒  尼奥
什么
What?
矩阵奴役着你
怎么回事
What the hell?
跟着小白兔
"跟着小白兔"
"Follow the white rabbit."
有人敲门  尼奥
是谁
Who is it?
是崔
It's Choi.
你迟到了两个小时
You're two hours late.
我知道  都怪她
I know. It's her fault.
带钱了吗
You got the money?
两千块
Two grand.
等着
Hold on.
哈利路亚
Hallelujah.
你是我的救星  伙计  是我的耶稣基督
You're my savior, man. My own personal Jesus Christ.
如果你用它的时候被抓...
You get caught using that...
我知道  这次交易没发生过  你并不存在
I know. This never happened. You don't exist.
-很好  -出什么事了吗  伙计
- Right. - Something wrong, man?
你比平时还要白
You look a little whiter than usual.
我的电脑
My computer, it...
你有没有过这种种感觉
Ever have that feeling where
不知道自己是醒着还是在梦中
you're not sure if you're awake or still dreaming?
嗑了药都这样
All the time. It's called mescaline.
这样才能飞起来
It's the only way to fly.
你好像需要放松放松[拔掉插头]  伙计
It just sounds to me like now you need to unplug, man.
好好休息下
Get some R and R?
你怎么想  杜朱  要不要带他一起去
What do you think, Dujour? Should we take him with us?
当然了
Definitely.
我去不了  我明天还要上班
No, I can't. I have work tomorrow.
别这样
Come on.
会很有趣的  我保证
It'll be fun. I promise.
好吧
Yeah.
我去
Sure. I'll go.
你好  尼奥
Hello, Neo.
-你怎么知道这个名字的  -我知道很多你的事
- How do you know that name? - I know a lot about you.
-你是谁  -我叫崔妮蒂
- Who are you? - My name is Trinity.
崔妮蒂
Trinity.
入侵国税局数据库的那个崔妮蒂
The Trinity? That cracked the IRS D-base?
那是很久以前的事了
That was a long time ago.
-上帝啊  -怎么了
- Jesus. - What?
我还以为
I just thought...
你是男人
you were a guy.
男人都这么想
Most guys do.
是你控制了我的电脑
That was you on my computer.
你怎么做到的
How did you do that?
现在  我只能告诉你
Right now, all I can tell you...
你有危险
...is that you're in danger.
-我要你来这是提醒你  -提醒我什么
- I brought you here to warn you. - Of what?
他们在监视你  尼奥
They're watching you, Neo.
-谁在监视我  -请听我说
- Who is? - Please just listen.
我知道你为什么来这儿  尼奥
I know why you're here, Neo.
我知道你做了些什么
I know what you've been doing.
我知道为什么你很少睡觉
I know why you hardly sleep...
为什么你一个人生活  以及为什么
why you live alone and why, night after night...
你会日以继夜的坐在电脑前
you sit at your computer.
你在找他
You're looking for him.
我知道  是因为我也曾找过他
I know, because I was once looking for the same thing.
而当他找到我的时候
And when he found me...
他告诉我  我其实不是在找他
he told me I wasn't really looking for him...
我是在寻找答案
I was looking for an answer.
是那个问题在驱使着我们  尼奥
It's the question that drives us, Neo.
是那个问题把你带到这儿来
It's the question that brought you here.
你和我一样
You know the question...
都知道是什么问题
just as I did.
什么是矩阵
What is the Matrix?
答案就在近前  尼奥
The answer is out there, Neo.
它也在寻找你
It's looking for you.
如果你愿意
And it will find you...
它最终会找到你
if you want it to.
操
Shit.
操  操
Shit, shit.
你不愿服从命令  安德森先生
You have a problem with authority, Mr. Anderson.
你认为你很特殊
You believe that you are special,
可以不受规矩的束缚
that somehow the rules do not apply to you.
很显然  你错了
Obviously, you are mistaken.
我们之所以能领跑软件行业
This company is one of the top software companies in the world...
是因为每个员工都自认是整体的一部分
because every single employee understands they are part of a whole.
因此  员工出了问题  公司就有了问题
Thus, if an employee has a problem, the company has a problem.
你该做出决定了  安德森先生
The time has come to make a choice, Mr. Anderson.
是从今天开始
Either you choose to be
准时来上班
at your desk on time from this day forth...
还是另谋高就
or you choose to find yourself another job.
清楚了吗
Do I make myself clear?
是的  莱因哈特先生  非常清楚
Yes, Mr. Rhineheart. Perfectly clear.
托马斯·安德森
Thomas Anderson?
是我
Yeah, that's me.
好的
Great.
祝你今天愉快
Have a nice day.
-你好  -你好  尼奥  知道我是谁吗
- Hello? - Hello, Neo, Do you know who this is?
-墨菲斯  -是的
- Morpheus. - Yes.
我一直在找你
I've been looking for you.
我想给你看些东西  不知你准备好了没有
I don't know if you're ready to see what I want to show you.
但是已经没时间了
But unfortunately, you and I have run out of time,
他们去找你了  尼奥
They're coming for you, Neo,
我不知道他们会做出什么
and I don't know what they're going to do,
谁来找我了
Who's coming for me?
站起来自己看吧
Stand up and see for yourself.
-现在吗  -是的
- What? Right now? - Yes, now.
慢慢站起来
Do it slowly.
看电梯的方向
The elevator.
-我操  -没错
- Oh, shit! - Yes.
他们想要什么
What the hell do they want from me?
我不知道  你要是不想知道
I don't know, but if you don't want to find out,
就赶快走
I suggest you get out of there.
怎么走
How?
我可以给你指路  但你必须严格按照我说的做
I can guide you, but you must do exactly as I say.
好的
Okay.
你对面的隔间是空着的
The cubicle across from you is empty.
-但是如果他们  -现在就去
- But what if they... - Go, Now.
先等一会
Stay here for just a moment.
听我的指令  走到这排的尽头
When I tell you, go to the end of the row...
到角落那间办公室里
to the office at the end of the hall.
身体尽量压低
Stay as low as you can.
现在走
Go! Now!
很好  窗外面有吊篮
Good, now, outside there is a scaffold.
-你怎么知道的  -没时间解释了
- How do you know all this? - We don't have time, Neo.
你的左边有扇窗户  过去
To your left there's a window, go to it.
打开
Open it.
用吊篮上屋顶
You can use the scaffold to get to the roof,
不行  你疯了吗
No way! No way! This is crazy!
只有两种方式离开这栋楼
There are two ways out of this building.
要么用吊篮  要么被他们押出去
One is that scaffold, the other is in their custody.
走哪条路  你自己决定吧
You take a chance either way, I leave it to you.
这太疯狂了
This is insane!
为什么会发生在我身上
Why is this happening to me?
我都做了些什么
What'd I do?
我无足轻重  什么都没做
I'm nobody. I didn't do anything.
我会死的
I'm gonna die.
操
Shit!
Oh, shit!
我办不到
I can't do this.
操
Shit.
你也知道了
As you can see, we've had
我们关注你有段时间了  安德森先生
our eye on you for some time now, Mr. Anderson.
从资料来看  你过着
It seems that you've been living...
两种生活
two lives.
第一种  你叫托马斯·A·安德森
In one life, you're Thomas A. Anderson...
知名软件公司的程序员
program writer for a respectable software company.
你有社保号  依法交税
You have a social security number. You pay your taxes.
你也会
And you...
帮房东太太扔垃圾
help your landlady carry out her garbage.
另一种是电脑里的生活
The other life is lived in computers...
你是个名叫尼奥的黑客
where you go by the hacker alias "Neo"...
跟电脑有关的法律
and are guilty of virtually
你差不多违反了个遍
every computer crime we have a law for.
有一种生活
One of these lives...
是有未来的
has a future.
另一种则没有
And one of them does not.
我跟你直说了吧  安德森先生
I'm going to be as forthcoming as I can be, Mr. Anderson.
你在这里
You're here...
是因为我们需要你的帮助
because we need your help.
我们知道有个人
We know that you've been contacted by a certain...
联系过你
individual.
一个自称为"墨菲斯"的人
A man who calls himself "Morpheus".
你怎么看这个人并不重要
Whatever you think you know about this man is irrelevant.
社会各界都认为
He is considered by many authorities...
他是最危险的人
to be the most dangerous man alive.
我的同事
My colleagues...
认为我是在跟你浪费时间
believe that I am wasting my time with you.
但是我认为你想做正确的事
But I believe you wish to do the right thing.
我们可以把旧账一笔勾销
We're willing to wipe the slate clean...
让你重新开始
give you a fresh start.
你只需要跟我们合作
All we're asking in return is your cooperation...
抓住这个臭名昭著的恐怖分子
in bringing a known terrorist to justice.
好吧
Yeah.
这交易挺不错
That sounds like a really good deal.
但是我有更好的
But I think I got a better one.
要不
How about...
我给你竖个中指
I give you the finger...
你让我打电话
and you give me my phone call.
安德森先生
Mr. Anderson...
你太让我失望了
you disappoint me.
别想用盖世太保那套吓唬我
You can't scare me with this gestapo crap.
我知道我的权利
I know my rights.
我要打电话
I want my phone call.
说说看  安德森先生
Tell me, Mr. Anderson...
要是你话都说不出来
what good is a phone call...
打电话还有什么用
if you're unable to speak?
你会帮我们的  安德森先生
You're going to help us, Mr. Anderson...
不管你愿不愿意
whether you want to or not.
线路被窃听了  我长话短说
This line is tapped, so I must be brief.
他们先找到你了
They got to you first,
但他们不知道你有多重要
but they've underestimated how important you are.
如果他们知道我所知道的事
If they knew what I know...
你恐怕已经死了
you would probably be dead.
你在说什么  我怎么了
What are you talking about? What is happening to me?
你是救世主  尼奥  也许这几年
You are the One, Neo. You see, you may have spent the last few years...
你一直在找我  但是我这一辈子
looking for me, but I've spent my entire life...
都在找你
looking for you.
你现在还想见我吗
Now, do you still want to meet?
-是的  -去亚当街的桥下
- Yes. - Then go to the Adams Street bridge.
进来
Get in.
-这是怎么回事  -这是必要的手段  尼奥
- What the hell is this? - It's necessary, Neo.
我们要保护自己
For our protection.
-谁会伤害你们  -你
- From what? - From you.
-脱衣服  -什么
- Take off your shirt. - What?
停车
Stop the car.
听好了  白痴
Listen, coppertop.
我们没空回答你的问题
We don't have time for 20 Questions.
现在只有一条规矩
Right now, there's only one rule:
听我们的
Our way...
不然就滚蛋
or the highway.
好吧
Fine.
求你了  尼奥  你要相信我
Please, Neo, you have to trust me.
-为什么  -因为你知道会发生什么  尼奥
- Why? - Because you have been down there, Neo.
你走过这条路
You know that road.
你知道尽头是什么
You know exactly where it ends.
而我知道你不想去那
And I know that's not where you want to be.
艾波克  开灯
Apoc, lights.
躺下  衣服掀起来
Lie back. Lift up your shirt.
-那是什么  -你被监控[植入虫子]了
- What's that? - We think you're bugged.
放松
Try and relax.
快点
Come on.
它想跑
It's on the move.
快点  混蛋
Come on, you shit.
-你会让它跑掉的  -我不会的
- You're gonna lose it. - No, I'm not.
准备
Clear!
上帝啊  那是真的
Jesus Christ! That thing's real?!
到地方了
This is it.
给你一个建议
Let me give you one piece of advice.
诚实些
Be honest.
他知道的远比你想象的多
He knows more than you can imagine.
终于见面了
At last.
欢迎  尼奥
Welcome, Neo.
你也猜到了吧
As you no doubt have guessed...
我是墨菲斯
I am Morpheus.
很荣幸见到你
It's an honor to meet you.
不
No...
是我很荣幸
the honor is mine.
请这边坐
Please, come. Sit.
我猜
I imagine...
你现在的感受有点像爱丽丝
that right now you're feeling a bit like Alice,
不小心跌进了兔子洞
tumbling down the rabbit hole?
可以这么说
You could say that.
我能从你眼中看出来
I can see it in your eyes.
我看出你是个敢接受现实的人
You have the look of a man who accepts what he sees,
因为你想醒过来
because he's expecting to wake up.
讽刺的是  我们现在离事实不远了
Ironically, this is not far from the truth.
你相信命运吗  尼奥
Do you believe in fate, Neo?
-不信  -为什么不信
- No. - Why not?
因为我不喜欢对自己的生活失去控制
Because I don't like the idea that I'm not in control of my life.
我完全明白你的意思
I know exactly what you mean.
我说说你来这的原因吧
Let me tell you why you're here.
你来这是因为你知道些什么
You're here brecause you know something.
却无法解释原因
What you know, you can't explain.
但你能感觉到
But you feel it.
你这一生都感觉得到
You felt it your entire life.
你感觉到这世界有些异样
That there's something wrong with the world.
你不知有何异样  但就是觉得不对
You don't know what it is, but it's there.
如同扎在心头的一根刺
Like a splinter in your mind,
直把你逼疯
driving you mad.
正是这种感觉把你带到了这
It is this feeling that has brought you to me.
你明白我在说什么吗
Do you know what I'm talking about?
矩阵吗
The Matrix?
你想知道
Do you want to know
矩阵是什么吗
what it is?
矩阵包罗万象
The Matrix is everywhere.
无所不在
It is all around us.
包括此刻  此地
Even now, in this very room.
你望向窗外  或是打开电视
You can see it when you look out your window,
都能看到它
or when you turn on your television.
你每次上班  去教堂
You can feel it when you go to work,
或是缴税
when you go to church,
都能感知到它
when you pay your taxes.
它就是你眼前的这个世界
It is the world that has been pulled over your eyes
挡住了背后的真相
to blind you from the truth.
什么真相
What truth?
你是一个奴隶  尼奥
That you are a slave, Neo.
和所有人一样  你生来即为奴
Like everyone else, you were born into bondage,
你生在一座自己感知不到的监狱
born into a prison that you cannot smell or taste or touch.
囚禁意识的监狱
A prison for your mind.
可惜矩阵是什么
Unfortunately, no one can be...
是说不清的
told what the Matrix is.
你必须亲眼得见
You have to see it for yourself.
这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance.
一旦做出选择  再无回头之路
After this, there is no turning back.
选择蓝色药丸
You take the blue pill,
到此为止  你就当是睡了一觉
the story ends, you wake up in your bed and believe
醒来继续过自己的日子
whatever you want to believe.
选择红色药丸
You take the red pill,
继续漫游仙境
you stay in Wonderland,
我带你见识一下这兔子洞有多深
and I show you how deep the rabbit hole goes.
记住
Remember,
我只是想告诉你真相
all I'm offering is the truth. Nothing more.
跟我来
Follow me.
艾波克  上线了吗
Apoc, are we on-line?
快了
Almost.
时间总是不够用
Time is always against us.
请坐在这里
Please take a seat there.
你也经历过这些
You did all this?
你服下的药丸是追踪程序的一部分
The pill you took is part of a trace program.
作用是干扰你的输入输出载波信号
It's designed to disrupt your input/outout carrier signals
方便给你定位
so we can pinpoint your location.
什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是系好安全带  妹子
It means buckle your seat belt, Dorothy,
跟你的老家
because Kansas
说再见吧
is going bye-bye.
你看没
Did you...
你可曾做过这样的梦  尼奥
Have you ever had a dream, Neo,
你坚信梦境就是现实
that you were so sure was real?
如果你醒不过来怎么办
What if you were unable to wake from that dream?
你又如何区分梦中世界
How would you know the difference between the dream world
和真实世界
and the real world?
-这不可能  -什么不可能
- This can't be. - Be what?
不可能是真的吗
Be real?
开始复制信号
It's going into replication.
-艾波克  -没搜索到
- Apoc? - Still nothing.
冷
It's cold.
好冷
It's cold!
坦克  尽快发信号过来
Tank, we're going to need a signal soon.
-检测到房颤  -艾波克  地址
- I got a fibrillation. - Apoc, location.
马上定位了
Targeting almost there.
他的心跳要停止了
He's going into arrest.
-锁定  我找到了  -坦克  就现在
- Lock. I got him! - Now, Tank, now!
欢迎
Welcome
来到真实的世界
to the real world.
我们成功了  崔妮蒂
We've done it, Trinity.
我们找到他了
We found him.
-希望你找对了人  -我不用希望
- I hope you're right. - I don't have to hope.
我相信
I know it.
我死了吗
Am I dead?
早着呢
Far from it.
他还需要恢复一段时间
He still needs a lot of work.
这是做什么
What are you doing?
你的肌肉萎缩了  这是帮你重生肌肉
Your muscles have atrophied. We're rebuilding them.
我的眼睛怎么这么疼
Why do my eyes hurt?
因为你从未睁开过双眼
You've never used them before.
休息吧尼奥  你会知道真相的
Rest, Neo. The answers are coming.
墨菲斯  我怎么了
Morpheus, what's happened to me?
这是哪里
What is this place?
你更应该问时间
More important than "what" is "when."
-时间  -你以为现在是1999年
- When? - You believe it's the year 1999,
其实更接近2199年
when in fact, it's closer to 2199.
我说不出具体是哪一年
I can't tell you exactly what year it is,
因为我们真的不知道
because we honestly don't know.
我无法用语言让你完全明白  尼奥
There's nothing I can say that will explain it for you, Neo.
随我来
Come with me.
你自己来看
See for yourself.
这是我的飞船
This is my ship.
尼布甲尼撒号  是一艘气垫船
The Nebuchadnezzar, It's a hovercraft.
这里是主甲板
This is the main deck.
这里是控制中枢
This is the core,
美国制造
我们在这里发射信号侵入矩阵
where we broadcast our pirate signal and hack into the Matrix.
我的船员你见过不少了
Most of my crew you already know.
这是艾波克
This is Apoc,
斯维奇
Switch,
而这是赛弗
and Cypher.
你没见过的是坦克和他哥哥多泽
The ones you don't know: Tank and his big brother, Dozer.
你身后的小家伙是耗子
The little one behind you is Mouse.
你想见识见识矩阵吗  尼奥
You wanted to know what the Matrix is, Neo?
崔妮蒂
Trinity.
放松
Try to relax.
你会觉得有点奇怪
This will feel a little weird.
这里
This
是主架构
is the Construct.
是我们的载入程序
It's our loading program.
我们可以载入任何东西  衣物
We can load anything, from clothing,
设备
to equipment,
武器
weapons,
拟真训练
training simulations,
应有尽有
anything we need.
我们这是在电脑程序里
Right now we're inside a computer program?
真的如此难以置信吗
Is it really so hard to believe?
你穿的衣服变了
Your clothes are different.
手臂上和脑后的插口也没了
The plugs in your arms and head are gone.
发型也变了
Your hair has changed.
你现在的形象叫做"自我形象残留"
Your appearance now is what we call "residual self-image."
是你对自己形象的心理映射
It is the mental projection of your digital self.
这些都不是真的
This isn't real?
什么是"真"
What is "real"?
又该如何定义"真"
How do you define "real"?
如果你指的是可被感知到
If you're talking about what you can feel,
被嗅到  被尝到  被看到
what you can smell, taste and see,
那所谓真实无非就是
then "real" is simply
经你大脑处理过的电信号
electrical signals interpreted by your brain.
这是你知道的那个世界
This is the world that you know.
那个世界尚处在20世纪末
The world as it was at the end of the 20th century.
其实只是神经交互模拟系统的一部分
It exists now only as part of a neural-interactive simulation
我们称为矩阵
that we call the Matrix.
你之前是在梦里生活  尼奥
You've been living in a dream world, Neo.
这个
This is the world
才是现实世界
as it exists today.
欢迎来到
Welcome to "the desert
真实的荒漠
of the real."
我们掌握的资料残缺不全
We have only bits and pieces of information.
但我们确知的是
But what we know for certain
在21世纪初的某个时刻
is that at some point in the early 21st century,
全世界普天同庆
all of mankind was united in celebration.
我们惊叹于自己的伟大成就
We marveled at our own magnificence
也就是AI的诞生
as we gave birth to A.I.
AI
A.I.
你是说人工智能
You mean artificial intelligence.
就是这个人工智能
A singular consciousness
让机器人种群繁衍壮大
that spawned an entire race of machines.
究竟是谁率先进攻已不得而知
We don't know who struck first, us or them.
不过是我们染黑了天空
But we know that it was us that scorched the sky.
当时  机器人十分依赖太阳能
At the time, they were dependent on solar power,
而人类相信  没了太阳
and it was believed that they would be unable to survive
这种持久的能源  机器人就无法生存
without an energy source as abundant as the sun.
纵观人类历史
Throughout human history,
我们的生活是那么依赖机器
we have been dependent on machines to survive.
命运就是这么讽刺
Fate, it seems, is not without a sense of irony.
人体产生的生物电
The human body generates
比一节120伏电池还多
more bioelectricity than a 120-volt battery.
还能产生超过25000BTU的体热
And over 25,000 BTUs of body heat.
机器用聚变的方式
Combined with a form of fusion,
获得了取之不尽的能源
the machines had found all the energy they would ever need.
在这些发电厂里  尼奥
There are fields, Neo, endless fields,
人类不是被生养出来
where human beings are no longer born.
而是被种植出来
We are grown.
好久以来  我并不相信
For the longest time, I wouldn't believe it.
直到我亲眼看见
And then I saw the fields with my own eyes,
看他们将死者液化
watched them liquefy the dead
来饲养活着的人
so they could be fed intravenously to the living.
我站在那  看机器物尽其用
And standing there, facing the pure, horrifying precision,
我终于知道事实就摆在眼前
I came to realize the obviousness of the truth.
矩阵究竟是什么
What is the Matrix?
是控制
Control.
矩阵就是电脑生成的虚幻世界
The Matrix is a computer-generated dream world,
用来控制所有人类
built to keep us under control,
并把一个活生生的人
in order to change a human being
变成这个
into this.
不
No.
我不信
I don't believe it.
这不可能
It's not possible.
我没说过这很容易接受  尼奥
I didn't say it would be easy, Neo.
但我说过  这就是真相
I just said it would be the truth.
停
Stop!
让我出去
Let me out!
放我出去  我要出去
Let me out! I want out!
-放松尼奥  放松  -把这玩意拔下来
- Easy, Neo. Easy. - Get this thing out of me.
快给我拔下来
Get this thing out of me!
别碰我
Don't touch me!
别过来
Stay away from me!
我不信
I don't believe it.
-他要跪  -呼吸  尼奥  深呼吸
- He's gonna pop. - Breathe, Neo. Just breathe.
我不能回头了  是不是
I can't go back, can I?
不能了
No.
就算你能回头
But if you could,
你还愿意回去吗
would you really want to?
我应该对你道歉
I feel I owe you an apology.
我们有条规矩
We have a rule.
我们解救的对象有年龄限制
We never free a mind once it's reached a certain age.
解救成年人很危险  他们不能放手
It's dangerous. The mind has trouble letting go.
我见过这样的事  我很抱歉
I've seen it before, and I'm sorry.
我这么做是因为
I did what I did because...
迫不得已
I had to.
矩阵初建之时  诞生了一个人
When the Matrix was first built, there was a man born inside,
他能够按照自己的心意
who had the ability to change whatever he wanted,
随意改变矩阵
to remake the Matrix as he saw fit.
就是他解放了我们的先民
It was he who freed the first of us,
告诉我们真相
taught us the truth.
只要矩阵还存在
As long as the Matrix exists,
人类就永远得不到自由
the human race will never be free.
他死后
After he died,
先知预言他会回来
the Oracle prophesied his return,
而这次
and that his coming
他会彻底摧毁矩阵
would hail the destruction of the Matrix,
终结这场战争
end the war,
还我们自由
bring freedom to our people.
所以有我这样的人
That is why there are those
终其一生在矩阵中寻找
of us who spent our lives searching the Matrix,
希望找到他
looking for him.
我这么做是因为
I did what I did because...
我相信我终于找到了
I believe that search is over.
好好休息吧
Get some rest.
以后用得上
You're going to need it.
做什么
For what?
训练
Your training.
早上好  昨晚睡了吗
Morning. Did you sleep?
今晚你就睡得着了
You will tonight.
我保证
I guarantee it.
我是坦克  你的接线员
I'm Tank. I'll be your operator.
-你胳膊上怎么没有  -插孔吗  没
- You don't have any... - Holes? Nope.
我和我哥多泽都是
Me and my brother, Dozer, are 100%
用最古老的方式降世的
pure, old-fashioned, homegrown human.
在这里出生
Born free right here,
现实世界里
in the real world.
锡安的孩子
Genuine child of Zion.
-锡安  -等战争胜利了
- Zion? - If the war was over tomorrow,
锡安会欢呼雀跃的
Zion's where the party would be.
那是座城市吗
It's a city?
最后的城市  仅存的人类聚居地
The last human city. The only place we have left.
在哪
Where is it?
深入地下
Deep underground,
接近地核  那里比较暖和
near the Earth's core, where it's still warm.
如果你命硬  没准还能亲眼看见呢
You live long enough, you might see it.
天杀的  说实话
Goddamn! I gotta tell you,
如果墨菲斯是对的
I feel the excited to see what you're capable of
我真想见识下你的本事
if Morpheus is right and all.
本来我不该说这个  但是
We're not supposed to talk about this, but...
如果你真是
if you are,
那就太棒了
it's a very exciting time.
今天事情不少  我们开始吧
We got a lot to do. We gotta get to it.
按理说  要先学基本操作
We're supposed to start with these operation programs first.
这是最无聊的
That's major boring shit.
咱应该来点带劲的
Let's do something a little more fun.
不如就来
How about...
格斗训练吧
combat training?
柔道
"Jujitsu"?
我要学柔道吗
I'm going to learn jujitsu?
我去
Holy shit!
"小麦  他居然喜欢"[麦片广告语]
"Hey, Mikey, I think he likes it."
还想再来些吗
How about some more?
要
Hell, yes.
当然要
Hell, yeah.
法国踢拳
美式空手道
跆拳道
醉拳
他学的怎样了
How is he?
连着学了十个小时  简直是台机器
Ten hours straight. He's a machine.
我会功夫了
I know kung fu.
给我露一手
Show me.
这是一个对练程序
This is a sparring program,
与矩阵中的世界相似
similar to the programmed reality of the Matrix.
有着相同的规矩  比如重力
It has the same basic rules. Rules like gravity.
你要知道这些规矩和计算机系统的规则
What you must learn is that these rules are no different than
没有什么不同
the rules of a computer system.
有些可以变通
Some of them can be bent.
有些可以打破
Others can be broken.
明白吗
Understand?
那有本事就来打我吧
Then hit me, if you can.
很好
Good!
适应环境
Adaptation.
随机应变
Improvisation.
但你的弱点
But your weakness
并不在招式
is not your technique.
墨菲斯和尼奥打起来了
Morpheus is fighting Neo.
我怎么打败你的
How did I beat you?
你太快了
You're too fast.
我在这里
Do you believe that
更强壮  更快
my being stronger or faster
和我的肌肉有关系吗
has anything to do with my muscles in this place?
你现在呼吸的是空气吗
You think that's air you're breathing now?
再来
Again!
老天爷  他真快
Jesus Christ, he's fast!
瞧他的神经元活动  远超常人了
Take a look at his neuro-kinetics, they are way above normal.
你在等什么
What are you waiting for?
你远比这个快
You're faster than this.
不要空想
Don't think you are.
相信自己
Know you are.
快点  别老想着打我  做出来
Come on! Stop trying to hit me, and hit me!
难以置信
I don't believe it.
我明白你想干什么了
I know what you're trying to do.
我想解放你的意识  尼奥
I'm trying to free your mind, Neo.
但我只能将你领到门口
But I can only show you the door.
你要自己走进去
You are the one that has to walk through it.
坦克  载入跳跃程序
Tank, load the jump program.
你必须放手  尼奥
You have to let it all go, Neo.
放下恐惧  迷惑和怀疑
Fear, doubt and disbelief.
解放你的意识
Free your mind.
好吧好吧
Okey-dokey.
解放我的意识
Free my mind.
要是他成功了呢
What if he makes it?
-第一次没人能跳过去  -我知道
- No one's ever made their first jump. - I know, I know.
-但如果他跳过去了呢  -不会的
- But what if he does? - He won't.
加油
Come on.
好吧
All right.
没问题的  解放意识
No problem. Free my mind.
解放意识  没问题  好的
Free my mind. No problem. Right.
这什么意思
What does that mean?
没什么意思
It doesn't mean anything.
第一次都会摔下去
Everybody falls the first time.
对吧  小崔
Right, Trin?
程序不是虚拟的吗
I thought it wasn't real.
你的意识让它成了真
Your mind makes it real.
如果在矩阵中被杀  就真的死了吗
If you're killed in the Matrix, you die here?
没了意识  身体没法存活
The body cannot live without the mind.
你都没给我送过晚饭
I don't remember you ever bringing me dinner.
他有些特别  是吗
There is something about him, isn't there?
你不会也信预言了吧
Don't tell me you're a believer now?
我只是好奇
I just keep wondering
如果墨菲斯如此确定
if Morpheus is so sure,
怎么不带他去见先知
why isn't he take him to see the Oracle?
等时机到了自然会去
Morpheus will take him when he's ready.
矩阵是一个系统  尼奥
The Matrix is a system, Neo.
这个系统是我们的敌人
That system is our enemy.
但身处其中时  你周围都是什么
But when you're inside, look around, what do you see?
商人  教师  律师  木匠
Businessmen, teachers, lawyers, carpenters.
我们就是要拯救这些人的意识
The very minds of the people we are trying to save.
但那之前  他们还是系统的一部分
But until we do, these people are a part of that system,
也就是我们的敌人
and that makes them our enemy.
你要明白
You have to understand,
大多数人都没准备好被拔掉插头
most of these people are not ready to be unplugged.
许多人深陷其中
And many of them are so inert
无比依赖这个系统
so hopelessly dependent on the system
甚至会奋起抵抗
that they will fight to protect it.
你是在听我说话呢
Were you listening to me Neo,
还是在看红衣女郎
or were you looking at the woman in the red dress?
-我在...  -再回头看看
- I was... - Look again.
定格
Freeze it.
这
This...
-这不是在矩阵中吗  -不
- This isn't the Matrix? - No.
这也是个训练程序
It's another training program
只为让你明白一个道理
designed to teach you one thing:
不属于我们  就是敌人
If you are not one of us, you are one of them.
-他们是谁  -监测程序
- What are they? - Sentient programs.
他们能自由进出
They can move in and out of
任何接入系统的程序
any software still hardwired to their system.
也就是说没有拔掉插头的人
That means that anyone we haven't unplugged
都可能变成特工
is potentially an agent.
在矩阵里
Inside the Matrix
他们无处不在
they are everyone,
却又遥不可及
and they are no one.
碰到他们  只能躲  或是跑
We have survived by hiding and running from them,
但他们也是矩阵的看门人
but they are the gatekeepers.
进出的关口全由他们把守
They're guarding all the doors, they're holding all the keys.
也就是说  总有人要和他们开战
Which means that sooner or later, someone will have to fight them.
总有人
Someone?
我不骗你  尼奥
I won't lie to you, Neo.
每个不屈服于他们
Every single man or woman who has stood their ground,
试图抗争的人都死了
everyone who has fought an agent has died.
你和他们不同  你会成功
But where they have failed, you will succeed.
为什么
Why?
我见过特工一拳打穿混凝土墙
I've seen an agent punch through a concrete wall.
子弹打光  却伤不到他们
Men have emptied entire clips at them and hit nothing but air.
可他们的力量与速度
Yet their strength and their speed
仍然受到矩阵规则的约束
are still based in a world that is built on rules.
因此
Because of that,
他们永远不可能比你更强  更快
they will never be as strong or as fast as you can be.
你想告诉我什么
What are you telling me?
我能躲子弹吗
That I can dodge bullets?
不  尼奥
No, Neo.
我是说  当时机成熟时
I'm trying to tell you that when you're ready,
你根本不需要躲
you won't have to.
我们遇到麻烦了
We got trouble.
-锡安发来的警告吗  -不  另一艘飞船发的
- Did Zion send the warning? - No, another ship.
该死
Shit.
-乌贼扫荡得真快  -乌贼
- Squiddy's sweeping in quick. - Squiddy?
就是哨兵  只有一条指令的杀戮机器
A sentinel. A killing machine designed for one thing.
搜索并摧毁
Search and destroy.
停在那吧
Set her down there.
情况如何  坦克
How are we doing, Tank?
电源关闭
Power off-line.
-EMP充能  就绪  -EMP
- EMP armed... and ready. - EMP?
电磁脉冲
Electromagnetic pulse.
能够使射程内所有电子系统失灵
Disables any electrical system in the blast radius.
是我们对抗机器人的唯一武器
It's the only weapon we have against the machines.
-我们在哪  -废弃的给排水系统系统里
- Where are we? - Their old service and waste systems.
下水道
Sewers.
上面本来有方圆百里的城市
There used to be cities that spanned hundreds of miles.
现在只剩下水道了
Now these sewers are all that's left.
安静
Quiet.
尼奥  把我魂都吓没了
Neo. You scared the bejesus out of me.
-抱歉  -没事
- Sorry. - It's okay.
-那是  -矩阵  没错
- Is that...? - The Matrix? Yeah.
-你习惯通过代码看它吗  -只能这样
- Do you always look at it encoded? - Well, you have to.
图像解析器只能用在主架构上
The image translators work for the construct program.
但矩阵的信息量太大  解码不了
But there's way too much information to decode the Matrix.
所以习惯以后  我眼中就没有代码
You get used to it. I don't even see the code.
只有金发妞  黑发妞  红发妞
All I see is blonde, brunette, redhead.
想喝一杯吗
You, uh, you want a drink?
好的
Sure.
我知道你在想什么
You know, I know what you're thinking.
因为我也一直这么想
Because right now I'm thinking the same thing.
事实上  我来到这就开始后悔了
Actually, I've been thinking it ever since I got here.
为什么当初没选蓝色的药丸
Why, oh, why didn't I take the blue pill?
好酒吧
Good shit, huh?
多泽酿的
Dozer makes it.
有两种用途
It's good for two things:
擦引擎和杀脑细胞
Degreasing engines and killing brain cells.
我能问你些事吗
So can I ask you something?
他说为什么这么做了吗
Did he tell you why he did it?
为什么选了你
Why you're here?
老天爷
Jesus!
给你洗脑了
What a mind job!
那你是来这拯救世界了
So you're here to save the world.
这种事能信吗
What do you say to something like that?
一点小建议
A little piece of advice.
如果遇到特工  还是像我们一样
You see an agent, you do what we do:
跑
Run.
拼了命地跑
You run your ass off.
谢谢你的酒
Thanks for the drink.
好梦
Sweet dreams.
说定了吗  里根先生
Do we have a deal, Mr. Reagan?
我知道这牛排不是真的
You know, I know this steak doesn't exist.
当我把它放进嘴里
I know that when I put it in my mouth,
矩阵会告诉我的大脑
the Matrix is telling my brain that it is,
它多汁又美味
juicy, and delicious.
九年了  知道我想通什么了吗
After nine years, you know what I realize?
无知是福
Ignorance is bliss.
那就是说定了
Then we have a deal.
我什么都不想记得
I don't want to remember nothing.
什么都不想  明白吗
Nothing. You understand?
我还要有钱
And I want to be rich.
做个有身份的人
You know, someone important.
比如演员什么的
Like an actor.
如你所愿  里根先生
Whatever you want, Mr. Reagan.
好吧
Okay.
把我的身体运回发电厂
You get my body back in a power plant,
将我的意识重新植入矩阵
reinsert me into the Matrix,
我就给你你要的东西
I'll get you what you want.
锡安主机的接入口令
Access codes to the Zion mainframe.
不  我告诉过你  口令我也不知道
No. I told you, I don't know them.
但我能给你知道口令的人
I can get you the man who does.
墨菲斯
Morpheus.
给你  伙计  冠军早餐
Here you go, buddy. Breakfast of champions.
闭上眼  吃起来就像软煎蛋
Close your eyes, it feels like you're eating runny eggs.
也像吃鼻涕
Or a bowl of snot.
你知道这让我想起什么吗
You know what it reminds me of?
麦好味麦片  你吃过麦好味吗
Tastee Wheat. Did you ever eat Tastee Wheat?
不  但是从理论上说  你也没吃过
No, but technically, neither did you.
说的就是这个
That's exactly my point. Exactly.
你想过吗
Because you have to wonder, now,
机器又怎么知道麦好味是什么味道呢
how do the machines really know what Tastee Wheat tasted like?
或许它们弄错了呢
Maybe they got it wrong.
或许麦好味实际上尝起来
Maybe what I think Tastee Wheat tasted like
就像燕麦粥或者金枪鱼一样
actually tasted like oatmeal or tuna fish.
这就更引人深思了
That makes you wonder about a lot of things.
就拿鸡肉来说
You take chicken for example,
或许它们不知道鸡肉的味道
maybe they couldn't figure out what to make chicken taste like,
所以鸡肉才有各种味道
which is why chicken tastes like everything.
-而且可能...  -闭嘴  耗子
- And maybe they... - Shut up, Mouse.
这就是种混合了合成氨基酸
It's a single-celled protein
维他命和矿物质的单细胞蛋白质
combined with synthetic aminos, vitamins and minerals.
你身体需要的都在这
Everything the body needs.
当然不都在这
It doesn't have everything the body needs.
听说你通过了特工训练程序
I understand you've run through the agent training program.
那个程序是我写的
You know, I wrote that program.
又来了
Here it comes.
-你觉得她怎么样  -谁
- So what did you think of her? - Of who?
红衣女郎  她是我设计的
The woman in the red dress. I designed her.
她话不多
She doesn't talk very much,
不过你想见她的话
but... but if you'd like to meet her,
我可以让她符合你的心意呢
I can arrange a much more personalized meeting.
虚拟皮条拉得真起劲
The digital pimp hard at work.
别管这些虚伪的家伙  尼奥
Pay no attention to these hypocrites, Neo.
否认自己的本能
To deny our own impulses
就是否认自己的人性
is to deny the very thing that makes us human.
多泽  吃完以后
Dozer, when you're done,
降到传输信号的深度
bring the ship up to broadcast depth.
我们要进入矩阵
We're going in.
我准备带尼奥去见她
I'm taking Neo to see her.
见谁
See who?
先知
The Oracle.
旅客们请注意
Everyone, please observe
"系好安全带"和"请勿吸烟"指示灯已亮
the "Fasten seat belt" and "No smoking" signs have been turned on.
请坐稳  享受本次旅途
Sit back and enjoy your flight.
我们进来了
We're in.
一小时内回来
We'll be back in an hour.
难以置信  对吗
Unbelievable, isn't it?
-天哪  -怎么了
- God! - What?
我在那家店吃过东西
I used to eat there.
面条很不错
Really good noodles.
我生活中的记忆
I have these memories from my life.
却都不是真的
None of them happened.
这意味着什么呢
What does that mean?
矩阵没法定义你
That the Matrix cannot tell you who you are.
先知就可以吗
But the Oracle can?
这是两码事
That's different.
你去找过她吗
Did you go to her?
去过
Yes.
她跟你说了些什么
What did she tell you?
她告诉我
She told me...
什么
What?
我们到了
We're here.
尼奥  跟我来
Neo, come with me.
这是那个作出预言的先知吗
So is this the same Oracle that made the prophecy?
对  她很老了
Yes. She's very old.
一开始她就支持着我们
She's been with us since the beginning.
-一开始  -抵抗运动的开始
- The beginning? - Of the Resistance.
那她什么都知道吗
And she knows what? Everything?
需要知道的她都知道
She would say she knows enough.
而且从未错过吗
And she's never wrong.
不要总想着对错
Try not to think of it in terms of right and wrong.
她只是向导  尼奥
She is a guide, Neo.
能帮你找到自己的道路
She can help you to find the path.
-她也帮过你吗  -是的
- She helped you? - Yes.
她跟你说了些什么
What did she tell you?
她说我会找到救世主
That I would find the One.
我说过我只能将你领到门口
I told you I can only show you the door.
你得自己走进去
You have to walk through it.
你好  尼奥
Hello, Neo.
来得正好
You're right on time.
请自便  墨菲斯  尼奥  跟我来
Make yourself at home, Morpheus. Neo, come with me.
这些是其他候选人
These are the other Potentials.
你在这等一会
You can wait here.
不要想着弄弯勺子
Do not try and bend the spoon.
那是不可能的
That's impossible.
你需要认清事实
Instead, only try to realize the truth.
什么事实
What truth?
根本没有勺子
There is no spoon.
没有勺子
There is no spoon?
然后你就会明白
Then you'll see that
弯曲的并不是勺子  而是你自己
it is not the spoon that bends. It is only yourself.
先知可以见你了
The Oracle will you see now.
我知道你是尼奥
I know you're Neo.
稍等我一下
Be right with you.
-你就是先知  -没错
- You're the Oracle? - Bingo.
跟你想象的不一样吧
Not quite what you were expecting, right?
就要出炉了
Almost done.
很香吧
Smell good, don't they?
我本来是要请你坐下的
I'd ask you to sit down...
不过反正你也不会坐
but you're not going to anyway.
-花瓶的事没关系  -什么花瓶
- And don't worry about the vase. - What vase?
那个花瓶
That vase.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我说过没关系
I said, don't worry about it.
我找个孩子补好吧
I'll get one of my kids to fix it.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
真正让你琢磨不透的是
What's really going to bake your noodle later on is
如果我不说  你还会打碎它吗
would you still have broken it if I hadn't said anything?
你比我想的还可爱
You're cuter than I thought.
我知道她为什么喜欢你了
I can see why she likes you.
谁喜欢我
Who?
可惜不怎么聪明
Not too bright, though.
你知道墨菲斯为什么带你来见我
You know why Morpheus brought you to see me.
那么
So...
你怎么想呢
what do you think?
你觉得自己是救世主吗
Do you think you are the One?
老实说  我不知道
Honestly, I don't know.
你能看懂那几个字吗
You know what that means?
那是拉丁语[temet nosce]
It's Latin.
意思是"认识自己"
Means, "Know thyself."
我告诉你个小秘密吧
I'll let you in on a little secret.
做救世主就跟恋爱一样
Being the One is just like being in love.
别人没法判断  但你就是知道
No one can tell you you're in love. You just know it
从头到尾
through and through.
无比深刻
Balls to bones.
好吧
Well,
让我仔细看看你
I'd better have a look at you.
张嘴  "啊"
Open your mouth. Say, "Ah."
好吧
Okay...
我应该说"挺有意思的  不过"
Now I'm supposed to say, "Hmm, that's interesting, but..."
然后你说
Then you say:
不过什么
But what?
不过你已经知道我要说什么了
But you already know what I'm going to tell you.
-我不是救世主  -抱歉  孩子
- I'm not the One. - Sorry, kid.
你有天赋
You got the gift
但你好像在等什么
but it looks like you're waiting for something.
-什么  -等来世吧  谁知道呢
- What? - Your next life, maybe. Who knows?
这种事总是这样
That's the way these things go.
-有什么好笑的  -墨菲斯
- What's funny? - Morpheus.
我差点就信他了
He almost had me convinced.
我明白
I know.
可怜的墨菲斯
Poor Morpheus.
没有他  我们就迷失了
Without him, we're lost.
你说"没有他"是什么意思
What do you mean, "without him"?
你确定想知道吗
Are you sure you want to hear this?
墨菲斯坚信你就是救世主  尼奥
Morpheus believes in you, Neo.
任何人  包括你  甚至包括我
And no one, not you, not even me
都无法动摇他的信念
can convince him otherwise.
他盲目地相信你
He believes it so blindly
甚至会为了救你而牺牲自己
that he's going to sacrifice his life to save yours.
-什么  -你将做出选择
- What? - You're going to have to make a choice.
你一只手握着墨菲斯的命
In the one hand, you'll have Morpheus' life.
另一只手里是自己的命
And in the other hand, you'll have your own.
你们中的一个会死
One of you is going to die.
至于是谁  就由你决定了
Which one will be up to you.
我很遗憾  孩子  真的
I'm sorry, kiddo. I really am.
你心地善良
You have a good soul.
我最讨厌告诉好人坏消息了
And I hate giving good people bad news.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
等你踏出那扇门
As soon as you step outside that door
你的心情会好起来的
you'll start feeling better.
你会想起来自己不信命运
You'll remember you don't believe in any of this fate crap.
你的生活自己掌控
You're in control of your own life.
记得吗
Remember?
给
Here,
吃块饼干吧
take a cookie.
我保证  等你吃完
I promise, by the time you're done eating it
心情马上就好了
you'll feel right as rain.
她说的话
What was said
是给你听的
was for you
不用说出来
and for you alone.
红衣女郎
他们快到了
They're on their way.
那是什么
What is that?
似曾相识
Oh, deja vu.
你刚才说什么
What did you just say?
没什么  就是有种似曾相识的感觉
Nothing. Just having a little deja vu.
-你看见什么了  -怎么了
- What did you see? - What happened?
刚有只黑猫走过去
A black cat went past us,
然后又过去一只一样的
then another just like it.
有多像  是同一只猫吗
How much like it? Was it the same cat?
有可能  我不确定
Might have been. I'm not sure.
斯维奇  艾波克
Switch, Apoc.
怎么了
What is it?
这种似曾相识
A deja vu is usually a
一般是矩阵被更改时
glitch in the Matrix which happens
出现的小故障
when they change something.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我们走
Let's go.
他们把电话线剪断了  是陷阱  快跑
They cut the hard line. It's a trap! Get out!
完了
Oh, no.
他们改了这个  咱们困在这出不去了
That's what they changed. We're trapped. There's no way out.
冷静点  把你电话给我
Be calm. Give me your phone.
他们会追踪到的
They'll be able to track it.
别无选择了
We have no choice.
接线员
Operator.
坦克  找一下这栋楼的结构图  快
Tank, find a structural drawing of this building, Find it fast.
-找到了  -主管道墙在哪
- Got it! - I need the main wet-wall.
十一楼
八楼
Eighth floor.
他们在八楼
They're on the eighth floor.
斯维奇  直走
Switch, straight ahead.
尼奥
Neo.
希望先知跟你说的是好消息
I hope the Oracle gave you some good news.
左转就是了
Now left, That's it,
很好
Good.
他们在哪
Where are they?
他们在墙里
They're in the walls.
在墙里
In the walls!
是个特工
It's an agent!
墨菲斯
Morpheus!
你们必须带尼奥走  他才是最重要的
You must get Neo out! He's all that matters!
不  墨菲斯  不要
No, Morpheus! Don't!
崔妮蒂  快走
Trinity, go!
走
Go!
-我们不能丢下他  -我们必须这么做
- We can't leave him! - We have to!
赛弗  快啊
Cypher! Come on!
伟大的墨菲斯  我们终于见面了
The great Morpheus. We meet at last.
你是哪位
And you are?
史密斯
A Smith.
史密斯特工
Agent Smith.
我看你们长得都一样
You all look the same to me.
交给你们了
Take him.
不
No!
-接线员  -我需要出口  快
- Operator. - I need an exit, fast,
刚才发生了车祸  天杀的车祸
There was an accident. Goddamn car accident.
突然间就撞车了
All of a sudden, boom,
我真命大啊
somebody up there still likes me.
放心  有我呢
I got you.
赶紧把我弄出去
Just get me out of here fast.
最近的在富兰克林和厄里街口
Nearest exit, Franklin and Erie.
是间老旧的电视修理店
An old TV repair shop.
好的
Right.
-接线员  -坦克  是我
- Operator. - Tank, it's me,
墨菲斯还活着吗
Is Morpheus alive?
墨菲斯还活着吗  坦克
Is Morpheus alive, Tank?
活着  他被带走了  不知道要去哪
Yes, They're moving him, I don't know where to yet.
他还活着  我们需要出口
He's alive. We need an exit.
你们离赛弗不远
You're not far from Cypher.
-赛弗  -想不到吧
- Cypher? - I know.
我让他去富兰克林和厄里街口了
I sent him to Franklin and Erie.
收到
Got it.
接到他了
Got him.
他们在哪
Where are they?
我正在打电话
Making the call.
很好
Good.
你先走  尼奥
You first, Neo.
该死
Shit!
我不知道  突然就断线了
I don't know. It just went dead.
你好  崔妮蒂
Hello, Trinity.
赛弗  坦克去哪了
Cypher? Where's Tank?
你知道吗
You know
好久以来
for a long time
我觉得自己爱上了你
I thought I was in love with you.
我总是梦到你
I used to dream about you.
你是个美人  崔妮蒂
You're a beautiful woman, Trinity.
走到这步真是可惜
Too bad things had to turn out this way.
你把他们杀了
You killed them.
-什么  -天啊
- What? - Oh, God.
我受够了  崔妮蒂
I'm tired, Trinity.
我受够了这场战争
I'm tired of this war
受够了打斗  受够了这飞船
tired of fighting. I'm tired of this ship
受够了挨冻和那恶心的糊糊
of being cold, of eating the same goddamn goop every day.
但是最主要的是
But most of all
我受够了那个混蛋和他的屁话
I'm tired of that jackoff and all of his bullshit.
想不到吧  混蛋
Surprise, asshole!
你没想到会有今天吧
I bet you never saw this coming,
对吧
did you?
天啊  真希望能亲眼
God, I wish I could be there
看着你屈服
when they break you.
我希望能在你屈服的那一刻走进去
I wish I could walk in just when it happens
这样一来
so right then
你就知道是我干的了
you'd know it was me.
-你出卖了墨菲斯  -他骗了我们  崔妮蒂
- You gave them Morpheus. - He lied to us, Trinity.
他把我们给耍了
He tricked us!
如果你早说实话
If you had told us the truth
我们他妈才不选红药丸呢
we would've told you to shove that red pill up your ass!
不是的  赛弗  他给了我们自由
That is not true, Cypher. He set us free.
"自由"
"Free".
你管这叫自由
You call this free?
每天按他的指示行事
All I do is what he tells me to do.
要我在这和矩阵之间选
If I had to choose between that and the Matrix,
我选择矩阵
I choose the Matrix.
矩阵不是真实的
The Matrix isn't real.
我不同意  崔妮蒂
I disagree, Trinity.
我认为矩阵
I think the Matrix
可以比这个世界更真实
can be more real than this world.
我在这边拔掉个插头
All I do is pull the plug here.
可在那边
But there
你就得看着艾波克死
you have to watch Apoc die.
崔妮蒂
Trinity.
不
No!
欢迎来到真实的世界
Welcome to the real world, lady.
可是你已经出来了  赛弗
But you're out, Cypher.
-你回不去了  -不  那是你的想法
- You can't go back. - Oh, no. That's what you think.
他们会把我的身体再放回去
They're gonnal reinsert my body,
我进入睡眠状态
I go back to sleep,
等我醒来  什么都不记得
and when I wake up, I won't remember a goddamn thing,
还有
By the way
要是有重要的话想对斯维奇说
if you have anything terribly important to say to Switch,
-就赶紧说吧  -求求你别这么做
- I suggest you say it now, - No, please don't.
我不要这样死
Not like this.
不要这样死
太迟了
Too late.
你个天杀的  赛弗
Goddamn you, Cypher!
别恨我  崔妮蒂
Don't hate me, Trinity.
我只是个传话的
I'm just a messenger.
现在  我要证明给你看
And right now, I'm going to prove it to you.
如果墨菲斯是对的
If Morpheus was right.
那我就拔不掉这个插头
there's no way I can pull this plug.
如果尼奥真的是救世主
If Neo's the One,
就一定会发生什么奇迹
then there'd have to be
来阻止我拔掉他的插头
some kind of a miracle to stop me.
对吧
Right?
他要是死了还怎么做救世主啊
I mean, how can he be the One if he's dead?
你以前从没告诉过我
You never did answer me before,
你到底信不信墨菲斯的屁话
if you bought into Morpheus' bullshit.
说嘛  我只想听信还是不信
Come on. All I want is a little yes or no.
看着他的眼睛
Look into his eyes,
那双又大又迷人的眼睛
those big, pretty eyes
然后告诉我
and tell me
信
yes
还是不信
or no,
我信
Yes.
不  这不可能
No, I don't believe it.
信不信由你  混蛋
Believe it or not, you piece of shit,
你总是要被烧死的
you're still going to burn!
你先走
You first.
你受伤了
You're hurt.
我没事
I'll be all right.
多泽呢
Dozer?
你有没有静静地观察过它
Have you ever stood and stared at it?
惊叹于它的美丽
Marveled at its beauty
天才的设计
its genius?
上亿的人们
Billions of people
每天就这么活着
just living out their lives.
一无所知
Oblivious.
你知不知道第一个矩阵
Did you know that the first Matrix
设计成了一个
was designed to be a
完美的人类世界  在那里无人受苦
perfect human world where none suffered
每个人都欢乐无比
where everyone would be happy.
结果却是场灾难
It was a disaster.
没人接受那个程序  那批人报废了
No one would accept the program. Entire crops were lost.
有些人认为
Some believe that
我们缺乏用来形容
we lacked the programming language
人类完美世界的程序语言
to describe your perfect world.
但是我认为  人类这个种族
But I believe that, as a species
认为艰难和困苦
human beings define their reality through misery...
才是真实
and suffering.
所谓完美世界只是
So the perfect world was a dream
你们那低级的大脑拼命想挣脱的梦境
that your primitive cerebrum kept trying to wake up from.
所以新的矩阵被设计成了这样
Which is why the Matrix was redesigned to this.
你们文明的巅峰
The peak of your civilization.
我说这是"你们的文明"
I say, "your civilization"
是因为一旦我们开始替你们思考
because as soon as we started thinking for you,
这就变成了我们的文明
it became our civilization
现在的情况正是这样
which is, of course, what this is all about.
进化  墨菲斯
Evolution, Morpheus.
进化
Evolution.
就像恐龙一样
Like the dinosaur.
看看窗外
Look out that window.
你们的时代结束了
You had your time.
未来是我们的  墨菲斯
The future is our world, Morpheus.
未来属于我们
The future is our time.
可能出了点问题
There could be a problem.
他们在对他做什么
What are they doing to him?
他们在入侵他的意识
They're breaking into his mind.
就好比黑入一台电脑  只是时间问题
It's like hacking a computer. All it takes is time.
需要多少时间
How much time?
取决于他的意识  但早晚会屈服
Depends on the mind. But eventually, it'll crack...
他的α脑电波会变成这样
and his alpha patterns will change from this to this.
那时候他什么都会交代
When it does, he'll tell them anything they want to know.
他们想要什么
What do they want?
每个舰长
The leader of every ship
都有锡安主机的接入口令
is given codes to Zion's mainframe computer.
如果有特工知道了密码
If an agent got the codes
进了锡安的主机
and got into Zion's mainframe...
他们会毁灭我们  不能发生这种情况
they could destroy us. We can't let that happen.
崔妮蒂
Trinity.
锡安的重要性远超过我
Zion's more important than me...
或是你
or you...
甚至是墨菲斯
or even Morpheus.
我们总能做点什么
There has to be something we can do.
当然可以  拔掉插头
There is. We pull the plug.
你要杀了他
You're going to kill him?
杀了墨菲斯
Kill Morpheus?
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
永远不要让人类做机器的工作
Never send a human to do a machine's job.
如果线人真的失败了
If indeed the insider has failed...
他们会尽快切断连接  除非
they'll sever the connection as soon as possible, unless...
他们已经死了  不管怎样
They're dead. In either case...
我们别无选择  只有按原计划进行
We have no choice. But continue as planned.
放出哨兵
Deploy the sentinels.
马上
Immediately.
墨菲斯  你不仅仅是我们的领袖
Morpheus, you were more than a leader to us.
更是我们的父亲
You were a father.
我们会永远想念你
We'll miss you always.
住手
Stop!
居然会这样
I don't believe this is happening.
-尼奥  必须如此  -真的吗
- Neo, this has to be done. - Does it?
我不知道
I don't know.
这不可能只是巧合  不可能
This can't be just coincidence. It can't be.
-你在说什么  -先知
- What are you talking about? - The Oracle.
她告诉过我会走到这步
She told me this would happen.
她说过我必须要做出选择
She told me that I would have to make a choice.
什么选择
What choice?
-你要干什么  -我要进去
- What are you doing? - I'm going in.
-不  不行  -我必须去
- No, you're not. - I have to.
尼奥  墨菲斯牺牲自己
Neo, Morpheus sacrificed himself
就是为了让我们带你出来
so that we could get you out.
绝不能再让你回去
There is no way that you're going back in.
墨菲斯那么做
Morpheus did what he did
是因为他错信了我的身份
because he believed I'm something I'm not.
-什么  -我不是救世主  崔妮蒂
- What? - I'm not the One, Trinity.
-先知说时我也很吃惊  -不  你必须是
- The Oracle hit me with that too. - No, you have to be.
很抱歉  我不是  我不过是个普通人
I'm sorry, I'm not. I'm just another guy.
不  尼奥  这不是真的
No, Neo, that's not true.
这不可能是真的
It can't be true.
为什么
Why?
尼奥  你疯了  他们把墨菲斯
Neo, this is loco. They've got Morpheus
关在由军队把守的建筑里
in a military-controlled building.
即便你命大能进到楼里
Even if you somehow got inside,
也有特工在看守他  三个都在
those are agents holding him. Three of them.
我也希望墨菲斯回来
I want Morpheus back too,
但你这就是去送死
but what you're talking about is suicide.
我知道看起来是这样  但并不是
I know that's what it looks like, but it's not.
我没法跟你解释为什么
I can't explain to you why it's not.
墨菲斯坚守一个信念
Morpheus believed something,
而他愿意为此付出他的生命
and he was ready to give his life for it.
现在我理解他了  所以我必须去
I understand that now. That's why I have to go.
-为什么  -因为我有自己的信念
- Why? - Because I believe in something.
是什么
What?
我相信我能带他回来
I believe I can bring him back.
-你要干什么  -跟你一起去
- What are you doing? - Going with you.
-不  不行  -不行
- No, you're not. - "No"?
让我告诉你我的信念
Let me tell you what I believe.
墨菲斯在我心里  比在你心里重要得多
I believe Morpheus means more to me than he does to you.
如果你真想救出他
I believe if you are serious about saving him,
你会需要我的帮助
you're going to need my help.
而且我现在是飞船上的最高长官
And since I am the ranking officer on the ship...
如果你不喜欢  就去死吧
if you don't like it, I believe you can go to hell.
因为你只有这一个下场
Because you aren't going anywhere else.
坦克
Tank...
带我们进去
load us up.
我想跟你分享下我在这里
I'd like to share a revelation that I've had...
悟出的一个道理
during my time here.
是我想给你们这个物种分类时想到的
It came to me when I tried to classify your species...
我意识到
and I realized that...
你们不算哺乳动物
you're not actually mammals.
这星球上的每一种哺乳动物
Every mammal on this planet...
都与周围环境
instinctively develops a natural equilibrium
发展出一种独特的平衡
with the surrounding environment.
你们人类却没有
But you humans do not.
你们进入一个区域  然后开始繁殖
You move to an area and you multiply...
不停繁殖直到自然资源枯竭
and multiply until every natural resource is consumed.
你们存活的唯一方式
The only way you can survive...
就是扩散到另一区域
is to spread to another area.
这星球上还有一个物种
There is another organism on this planet...
跟你们的生存方式一样
that follows the same pattern.
你知道是什么吗
Do you know what it is?
病毒
A virus.
人类就是疾病
Human beings are a disease.
这个星球的肿瘤
A cancer of this planet.
你们就是瘟疫
You are a plague.
而我们是解药
And we are the cure.
好吧  你需要什么
Okay, so what do you need?
除了奇迹之外
Besides a miracle.
枪
Guns.
很多的枪
Lots of guns.
从没人做过这种事
No one has ever done anything like this.
所以我们一定会成功
That's why it's going to work.
注射了怎么还没反应
Why isn't the serum working?
也许他根本就不知道
Perhaps we're asking the wrong questions.
让我跟他独处
Leave me with him.
马上
Now.
撑住啊  墨菲斯
Hold on, Morpheus.
他们去救你了  他们很快就到
They're coming for you. They're coming.
你能听见吗  墨菲斯
Can you hear me, Morpheus?
我要跟你
I'm going to be honest...
坦白
with you.
我
I...
讨厌
hate...
这个地方
this place...
这个动物园
this zoo...
这座监狱
this prison...
这种现实  叫什么都行
this reality, whatever you want to call it.
我真的受不了了
I can't stand it any longer.
这里的气味
It's the smell.
如果真有这种东西的话
If there is such a thing.
我已经受够了
I feel saturated by it.
我能尝到
I can taste...
你的恶臭
your stink.
每次我闻到
And every time I do,
我都担心自己被它传染
I fear that I have somehow been infected by it.
真是恶心
It's repulsive.
对吧
Isn't it?
我必须离开这
I must get out of here.
我必须获得自由
I must get free.
而钥匙就在你的意识里
And in this mind is the key.
我的钥匙
My key.
摧毁了锡安  我就不用再待在这了
Once Zion is destroyed, there is no need for me to be here.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
我需要密码
I need the codes.
我必须进入锡安
I have to get inside Zion...
而你必须告诉我方法
and you have to tell me how.
你要么告诉我方法
You're going to tell me...
要么就死在这
or you're going to die.
请拿掉身上
Please remove any metallic
所有的金属物品  钥匙  硬币
items you're carrying. Keys, loose change.
我操
Holy shit!
支援  请求支援
Backup. Send backup.
不许动
Freeze!
你之前在干什么
What were you doing?
他还不知道
He doesn't know.
知道什么
Know what?
看来他们是想救他
I think they're trying to save him.
根本没有勺子
There is no spoon.
找到他们  干掉他们
Find them and destroy them!
重复  我们遭到袭击
I repeat. We're under attack!
崔妮蒂  帮我
Trinity! Help!
凡人而已
Only human.
有种躲这个
Dodge this.
-你怎么做到的  -做什么
- How did you do that? - Do what?
你能像他们一样
You moved like they do.
我没见过谁有那么快
I've never seen anyone move that fast.
还不够快
It wasn't fast enough.
你会开那个吗
Can you fly that thing?
现在还不会
Not yet.
接线员
Operator.
坦克  我需要B212直升机的驾驶员程序
Tank, I need a pilot program for a B-212 helicopter.
快点
Hurry.
我们走
Let's go.
不好
No.
墨菲斯  站起来  起来  快起来
Morpheus, get up. Get up, get up.
他跳不过来的
He's not going to make it.
抓住你了
Got you.
我就知道
I knew it.
他是救世主
He's the One.
你现在相信了吗  崔妮蒂
Do you believe it now, Trinity?
墨菲斯
Morpheus.
先知
The Oracle.
-她告诉我  -她告诉你的
- She told me... - She told you...
只是你需要知道的
what you needed to hear.
仅此而已
That's all.
尼奥  你早晚会领悟这一点  就跟我一样
Neo, Sooner or later you'll realize, just as I did.
知其路  与行其事
There's a difference between knowing the path...
并不相同
and walking the path.
-接线员  -坦克
- Operator. - Tank.
我的天  能听到你声音真是太棒了  长官
God damn it. It's good to hear your voice, Sir.
我们需要出口
We need an exit.
准备好了
Got one ready.
地铁  斯泰特和巴伯阿站
Subway station, State and Balboa.
该死
Damn it!
追踪完毕
The trace was completed.
找到他们的位置了
We have their position.
哨兵已准备就绪
Sentinels are standing by.
下令攻击吧
Order the strike.
他们还没出去呢
They're not out yet.
你先  墨菲斯
You first, Morpheus.
尼奥  有些事我想告诉你
Neo, I want to tell you something...
但我害怕  如果我说了将意味着什么
but I'm afraid of what it could mean if I do.
先知告诉我的所有事都成真了
Everything the Oracle told me has come true.
唯有这一件没有
Everything but this.
哪一件
But what?
尼奥
Neo.
-出了什么事  -特工
- What the hell just happened? - An agent.
-你得送我回去  -我做不到
- You have to send me back. - I can't.
安德森先生
Mr. Anderson.
跑啊  尼奥  快跑
Run, Neo. Run.
他在干什么
What is he doing?
他开始相信了
He's beginning to believe.
你没子弹了
You're empty.
你也是
So are you.
我很享受看着你死去
I'm going to enjoy watching you die...
安德森先生
Mr. Anderson.
老天  他会被打死的
Jesus, he's killing him.
你听到了吗  安德森先生
You hear that, Mr. Anderson?
这是你逃不掉的呼唤
That is the sound of inevitability.
是你的丧钟
It is the sound of your death.
再见  安德森先生
Goodbye, Mr. Anderson.
我的名字
My name...
叫尼奥
is Neo.
发生了什么
What happened?
我不知道  追踪不到他了
I don't know. I lost him.
接近警报
该死
Oh, shit.
是哨兵
Sentinels.
-还有多久  -五六分钟吧
- How long? - Five, maybe six minutes.
坦克  给电磁脉冲充电
Tank, charge the EMP.
他出来之前我们不能用
We can't use that until he's out.
我知道  崔妮蒂  别担心
I know, Trinity. Don't worry.
他会回来的
He's gonna make it.
平底鞋还是高跟鞋  不行  你就
Flat or pumps? No, just...
干什么  那是我的手机
What the shit? That's my phone!
那家伙抢了我的手机
That guy took my phone!
-找到他了  他正在逃跑  -神奇先生
- Got him! He's on the run. - Mr. Wizard,
带我离开这吧
get me out of here!
有个老出口  沃巴什和雷克街口
I got an old exit, Wabash and Lake.
妈的
Oh, shit!
帮帮我  帮我点小忙
Help! Need a little help!
那扇门
The door.
左边那扇门
The door on your left.
另一个边
Your other left!
走后门
The back door.
不好
Oh, no.
它们来了
Here they come.
他会成功的
He's going to make it.
巷子尽头的救生梯  去303号房
The fire escape at the end of the alley, Room 303,
它们进来了
They're inside.
快啊  尼奥
Hurry, Neo.
这不可能
It can't be.
检查下他
Check him.
他死了
He's gone.
再见  安德森先生
Goodbye, Mr. Anderson.
我不再害怕了
I'm not afraid anymore.
先知告诉我
The Oracle told me...
我会爱上那个男人
that I'd fall in love with that man.
我爱上的男人是救世主
The man that I love would be the One.
所以你看
So you see...
你不能死
you can't be dead.
You can't be...
因为我爱你
because I love you.
你听到了吗
You hear me?
我爱你
I love you.
现在  起来吧
Now, get up.
不行
No.
怎么做到的
How?
他是救世主
He is the One.
电话  已接通
我知道你在那
I know you're out there,
警告  运营商异常
我能感觉到你
I can feel you now,
追踪程序  运行中
你害怕我们
you're afraid of us,
害怕改变
you're afraid of change,
系统崩溃
我无法预知未来
I don't know the future,
我并不是来告诉你  一切将如何结束
I didn't come here to tell you how this is going to end,
我是来告诉你  一切将怎样开始
I came here to tell you how it's going to begin.
我会挂断这通电话
I'll hang up this phone,
之后我会给这些人展示
and then I'll show these people
你不愿让他们看到的东西
what you don't want them to see,
我会让他们看到一个崭新的世界
I'm going to show them a world...
没有你
without you,
没有规矩和控制
a world without rules and controls,
没有国界或界限
without borders or boundaries,
一个万事皆有可能的世界
a world where anything is possible,
在那之后
where we go from there...
选择权在你手上
is a choice I leave to you,